<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Remote Development using SSH</title>
      <link>/remote-development-using-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/remote-development-using-ssh/</guid>
      <description>If you need to edit and debug on a remote machine with VS Code, Install Visual Studio Code Remote - SSH extension which helps connect to a remote running SSH server and take full advantage of VS Code&amp;rsquo;s feature set.
Prerequisites:
To get started, you need to have done the following steps:
Install an OpenSSH compatible SSH client (PuTTY is not supported). Details of remote host machine with pre installed home-creators, SSH username and private Key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use temporary email address</title>
      <link>/how-to-use-temporary-email-address/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-use-temporary-email-address/</guid>
      <description>All of the websites need to submit emails nowadays. But when ever we submit the email address to any website from the next day onwards we will start getting spam Mails from the registered application. Trying to solve this by two easy hacks
Use Temporary emails Link to heading There are some websites which allow us to get temporary email address and its inbox for a short span of time. FOr registering and testing we can use the email address and its inbox to see the mails received</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fork a github repo and give a pull request</title>
      <link>/how-to-fork-a-github-repo-and-give-a-pull-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-fork-a-github-repo-and-give-a-pull-request/</guid>
      <description>You found a useful repository in github. You have some suggestions to the owner of git hub.Do you try to find out owners email and send a email to him about that repo? What is the standard way to modify the content of that repo?
For this we have to do the following
Fork the original repo to our github Clone forked repo to our machine Create a branch Make our changes on that branch Push it back to our repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Search Useful Tips and Tricks</title>
      <link>/google-search-useful-tips-and-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/google-search-useful-tips-and-tricks/</guid>
      <description>Internet is everything in these days. We can get any kind of information from the era of internet and Google. Most of us rely on Google for searching the data and finding details from Google. Normally we type what we required to to search in google home page and click on the links which we got from there.
By using some simple techniques we can refine the data that we are looking for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is CKAN</title>
      <link>/what-is-ckan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what-is-ckan/</guid>
      <description>CKAN stands for Comprehensive Knowledge Archive Network. CKAN is a self-described data portal platform that allows an organization to manage, publish, and share data and for others to find and use that data. It is a tool for making open data websites.It helps you manage and publish collections of data. It is used by national and local governments, research institutions, and other organizations who collect a lot of data.
Once your data is published, users can use its faceted search features to browse and find the data they need, and preview it using maps, graphs and tables - whether they are developers, journalists, researchers, NGOs, citizens, or even your own staff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to generate submodules</title>
      <link>/how-to-generate-submodules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-generate-submodules/</guid>
      <description>Suppose we have a project named &amp;lsquo;flower&amp;rsquo; with different people working on it. Suppose some other team already created a repository named &amp;lsquo;Rose&amp;rsquo; which can add as a sub directory under our existing &amp;lsquo;flower&amp;rsquo; repository.
git submodule add https://github.com/&amp;lt;user&amp;gt;/rose rose At this point, you’ll have a rose folder inside flower, but if you were to check inside that folder, depending on your version of Git, you might see … nothing. Newer versions of Git will do this automatically, but older versions will require you to explicitly tell Git to download the contents of rose:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostGraphile</title>
      <link>/postgraphile/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/postgraphile/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;PostGraphile&amp;rdquo; is a instant, secure and fast GraphQL API for PostgresSQL. This builds and serves a client-facing GraphQL API by inspecting your existing database (tables, columns, relations, views, procedures and more). No GraphQL coding necessary to get the data from an existing Schema or Database.This works with Apollo, Relay Modern and most other GraphQL clients. Enforce user permissions at the data level using PostgreSQL&amp;rsquo;s well established, granular and trusted Role-Based Access Control (RBAC) and Row-Level Security (RLS) features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmatic User creation and Welcome mail with customized contents from entities - Drupal 7</title>
      <link>/programmatic-user-creation-and-welcome-mail-with-customized-contents-from-entities-drupal-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/programmatic-user-creation-and-welcome-mail-with-customized-contents-from-entities-drupal-7/</guid>
      <description>Consider a case that we need to add a drupal user when we create a content type and that specific drupal user has first name and last name and contact details from a node. Usual way to create a Drupal user is to use the method user_save as the following way. For sending message we can set default mail alert from &amp;ldquo;Configuration -&amp;gt; Account Settings -&amp;gt; Email Alerts Section &amp;quot; as explained below</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is GDPR</title>
      <link>/what-is-gdpr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what-is-gdpr/</guid>
      <description>GDPR ( General Data Protection Regulation) is an EU regulation that intends to provide protection to personal data of the EU citizens and increase the constraints on organizations who handle these personal data. GDPR law applies to all companies that collect and process data belonging to EU citizens. Its major concern is data protection for individuals within the European Union and manages the export of personal data outside the EU. The primary objective of GDPR is to give citizens back control of their personal data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working WSL2 Debian in Windows10</title>
      <link>/working-wsl2-debian-in-windows10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-wsl2-debian-in-windows10/</guid>
      <description>We can configure Debian Linux from our Windows 10 machine as Windows App. When we work with static site generators like Hugo or need to check any thing in linux from linux machine we can choose this method of linux
If you have confusions in how to install a Ubuntu subversion you can go through my previous post: Install the Windows Subsystem for Linux
For configuring this in our Windows10 machine we need to follow the following steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can we work Ubuntu from Windows10</title>
      <link>/how-can-we-work-ubuntu-from-windows10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-can-we-work-ubuntu-from-windows10/</guid>
      <description>We can configure Ubuntu Linux from your Windows 10 machine as Windows App. When we work with static site generators like Hugo or need to check any thing in linux from linux machine we can choose this method of linux
For configuring this in our Windows10 machine we need to follow the following steps.
Initial Settings Link to heading When we start directly install the Linux app in windows we may face an issue that Subsystem not enabled &amp;ldquo;Press any key to continue&amp;rdquo; in linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 22:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Geo is a highly skilled software engineer with more than 12 years of experience in the IT industry. He has excellent exposure to PHP, MySQL, Drupal, JavaScript,Angular,GraphQL,Hugo, jQuery, CSS/HTML,Mirth Connect and other open source development technologies including Cross Domain API Implementation and Widgets. He has strong analysis, problem solving and testing skills. Being self motivated, he has an ardent drive and desire to create new things. He is a terrific engineer that saturnine quality code within the expected project timelines.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
